Carlos Junod

Full Stack Developer - UI/UX Designer

+1 (321) 352 0116 hello@carlosjunod.me www.carlosjunod.me

About Me:

Over the past 8 years, I have developed enterprise-grade applications using Node.js (express.js), Java (Spring Boot), and JavaScript (+TypeScript) with libraries like React, Redux/MobX. I have also implemented CD/CI pipelines with tools such as Jenkins, OpenShift / Kubernetes to optimize and automate unit testing, reducing delivery time for the team.

Key Skills

Front-End
JavaScript
React.js
Redux / MobX
Next.js
Jest / Mocha / Chai /
React Testing Library
React Native
Webpack
CSS 3 / HTML 5
Sass, Less, Stylus
Tailwind
Bootstrap / Foundation
jQuery

Backend Node.js (Express.js) Java (Spring Boot) PHP (Laravel) Data Bases Relational (Oracle SQL, MySql, DynamoDB) Non-Relational

Cloud Services **AWS** (IAM, EC2, S3, Lambda, DynamoDB) **Azure**

DevOps
OpenShift
Jenkins
CD/CI
Kubernetes

(MongoDB)

Agile Methodology tools Strong Agile oriented Jira Rally Software

Others
Spanish (Native language)
WordPress (themes and plug-ins)

Design Tools Figma Adobe XD Sketch Illustrator Photoshop

Work History

Walmart Tech

Front End Developer Sunny Valley, CA (Remote) Apr 2022 – Current Front End developer at the Sams's Club's Checkout page Team (web app), My principal responsibilities are:

- O Creation and maintain reusable components in React.js.
- Writing and improving unit tests (React Testing Library)
- Working on the creation and implementation of an internal UI library (Tailwind/React.js)

o Implementation of new features (Front-end).

Used Technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Redux, Stylus, Tailwind, Next.js, (WCNP) is a Kubernetes-based platform, Jenkins

Sillicon Valley Bank

Front End Developer Sun Valley, CA (Remote) Jun 2021 – Apr 2022 Full Stack developer of internal workflow application My principal responsibilities are:

- Creation of reusable components in React.js.
- Redesigning pre-existing front-end architecture.
- o Implementation of new features (front-end).
- Developing new user interfaces (UI/UX).
- Creation of complex forms and validation
- Maintain and develop existing web components.

Used Technologies: TypeScript, React.js, MobX, CSS3, HTML, Webpack, OpenShift, Jenkins.

Florida Blue

Full stack developer Jacksonville, FL Jan 2020 – Jun 2021 Full Stack developer of internal workflow application My principal responsibilities are:

- Creation of reusable components in React.js.
- o Redesigning pre-existing front-end architecture.
- o Implementation of new features (backend and frontend).
- Designing / Developing new user interfaces (UI/UX).
- Creation of complex forms and validation,
- Maintain and develop existing API endpoints in Java SpringBoot

Used Technologies: JavaScript, React.js, CSS3, HTML, Webpack, Java, SpringBoot, Oracle SQL, Jenkins, OpenShift

Brooksource

Full stack developer Jacksonville, FL Jun 2018 - Jan 2020 As a Front-end developer at Technical Youth, I worked with their largest client building the front-end and proxy layer for an internal tiered approval process application based on web technologies. This application allows multiple users with different roles to submit, manage, and rework requests within the approval workflow. Other key features include form validation and file attachment uploading. Responsibilities:

- Front-end Development based on provided mockups
- Creation of reusable components in React.is.
- Creation Proxy Server Node.js
- Creation of complex forms and validation.

Used Technologies: JavaScript, React.js, CSS3, HTML, Webpack, Node.js, Express.js, Oracle SQL, Jenkins, OpenShift.

Simplicity Solutions

Orange City, FL Developer – UX Designer Nov 2017 - Jun 2018 As a Developer and Designer, I was able to work in different roles for various projects doing front-end and back-end development, UX design, ecommerce development, mobile applications, WordPress + WooComerce development for companies such as eatnakedla.com, burstvr.com, Guidecentral (web and mobile app).

Used Technologies/Applications: JavaScript, CSS 3, SASS, HTML 5, PHP, WordPress, AWS (IAM, Lamda Functions), Maria DB, Ionic, Apache Cordova, Photoshop, Illustrator, inVision.

Huella Producciones

Art Director / Web developer
Temuco, Chile
Jan 2010 - Dec 2014

As one of the founders of Huella Producciones I oversaw art direction and the quality assessment of all the products we shipped for our government and private clients. Also, I developed/oversaw more than hundred WordPress themes for government web projects and multiple branding creation for government supported companies. In addition, I was in charge of the recruitment of new designers and developers.

Used Technologies/Applications: JavaScript, jQuery, CSS 3, SASS, HTML 5, PHP, WordPress, MySQL, Bootstrap, Zurb Foundation, ActionScript, Phyton, Django Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Adobe Flash.

Education

2017 B.S. Web Design & Development Full Sail University (Winter Park, FL)

2015 English as Second Language (ESL) Full Sail University (Winter Park, FL)

2011 Bootcamp web manager & design pro. Academia Mac – UGM Santiago, Chile.

2010 Advance Search Marketing. SEO training Buenos Aires, Argentina

2008 B.S. Graphic Design. INACAP (Temuco, Chile)

Activities & Awards

Course Director's Award (Project and Portfolio I: Development)

Course Director's Award (Design for Web Standards)

Course Director's Award (Project and Portfolio IV: Design & Development)

Front-End Developer for Adopets.com (2015)